Ugh, you sure this is the place?
Yeah. I think this is it, probably.
Oh well, figure it out once you get there!
Whoa, hold on—
So how did it go?
What was that world like?
White-knuckle! If Asakaze hadn't been there, we'd be dead.
It was no big deal.
There you go again, acting cool.
Nagara found today's portal too.
Yeah? That's incredible.
That's his 13th one this week.
All coincidences, right?
That's right. Coincidences.
It just sort of happens.
Coincidences, eh?
I put together this report on Nozomi's power.
I've had her observe the light that her
Compass indicates for the past month,
but I still haven't been able to figure out what it is.
No matter how close we get,
it always maintains the same distance,
and there's nothing we can do to affect it.
It appears to exist in a domain that cannot be observed by us.
So how do we get to this place?
Yeah, that is the question.
Also, Nozomi is the only one who can see this light, right?
Does it even really exist to begin with?
Don't worry.
I'm absolutely certain of it.
Yeah, but whether it's a way out is...
It's starting to rain.
There may be other powers that we don't know about yet.
Also, investigating the worlds inside the school,
and perhaps what the light is,
might reveal how we can get home.
Yeah, maybe it will.
But what is this world?
And who exactly gave us these powers?
Yesterday, Murayama,
who had been missing, was found in the jungle.
Albeit under somewhat unusual circumstances.
Here is a picture of him.
Ew...
He's like a zombie.
Is there anyone here who might know
if this is a result of another new rule in this world,
or if this happened because of someone's power?
Yes, please.
This may be totally unrelated,
but Inuyama also went missing about a week ago.
A week ago? Why didn't you say anything until now?
Huh? I thought someone else would notice and say something.
Guess nobody was missing him.
He may have gotten himself into trouble.
We also need to investigate this freezing phenomenon.
Anyone?
Unlike a certain someone,
we don't have the time or any special powers.
I suppose you're right.
Huh?
You don't have to work, and you've got the time, right?
Would it hurt to work with the others a little more—
Pass.
Well, shall we vote on it, then?
Nice and fair.
Fine.
I'll do it.
Oh. Then please do.
But it's too much for just one person, so can I ask for an assistant?
So, why me?
I don't think I'm going to be much help with this.
Be quiet for a sec.
Okay, so I was thinking of streaming a new game today,
and so I've settled on this! Ta-da!
Is this guy for real?
Huh? What is it?
H-He's streaming a game.
Really? How?
That's what I'd like to know.
Whatever, let's go find the other one.
Over there...
Hey, are you Inuyama?
Yeah, you're Inuyama.
Just like Mura.
Is he streaming a game?
No.
Then what's he doing?
...two... three... four...
H-He's working out.
I've got it—
what these two frozen guys have in common.
What is it?
They're both guys that nobody notices whether they're there or not.
That's why nobody raised a big fuss when they left.
But, there's not much we can do until we figure out what's causing the freezing in the first place.
Let's start with that.
How do we do that?
Investigation lesson one: question involved parties.
Oh, that, huh?
Look, let me make one thing clear...
I'm the boss, and you're just my assistant,
so keep quiet and do what I tell you to.
Got it?
I got it.
Very good.
Okay, here you go.
This one's yours.
Don't sweat it, it's my treat.
You could give stuff to everyone else for free too, you know.
Why put them through the
trouble of settling payments?
Because right here and now, this is reality.
Did rich people give you stuff for free back in the real world?
No, I know, but still...
What, you got a problem with that?
With the app, if you don't pay back every little bit that you owe,
your stuff ends up burning to a crisp in that blue fire.
Which makes it so everyone has to work all day long.
Like I said, no different than how it was before, right?
That's what happens when you laze about for so long.
This is reality in a capitalist society. Get it?
Mura?
He seemed fine.
There was no sign that anything was particularly off with him.
He's turned pitch-black and stopped moving, right?
You don't think it's some weird disease, do you? Could it be contagious?
Yeah, dunno.
No slacking off!
Oh, him?
Yeah, I heard he used to stream games.
Apparently he didn't even have a single subscriber, though.
Does that have anything to do with this?
Inuyama? Inuyama, Inuyama...
He was here until not too long ago.
You don't know anything about him?
Ah, I remember now.
He went drifting off, too. I didn't notice.
Got it. We're done here.
Oh, hold on.
Let's have some fun together.
I'd love to get to know you better.
Not me, but my power, right?
Come to think of it, Mizuho,
what are your cats doing here?
They aren't mine.
These are actually my grandma's cats.
But my grandma got dementia,
and wound up in a home.
But nobody wanted to look after these guys,
and I heard they were going to get rid of them.
So I stuffed them in my bag and took them away.
Are you gonna tell the others?
No, I won't. And even if I did...
Oh, and I could use my power before we went adrift.
Huh?
There's a good boy.
Wait, how'd that work?
I could only use it at school.
I'm sure there were others who had powers besides me, too.
A strange power you can use while at school...
Oh, it's you.
What's up?
Just a little curious.
Was this caused by this world's rules?
Or maybe someone's power?
That's a good question.
We're trapped here,
engulfed in flames, bound by a set of rules.
That's how it's been ever since we went adrift.
It's almost as if someone's testing us, huh?
And who could that be?
You don't think...
You knew, didn't you?
That the school would go adrift,
and that we'd end up like this.
You're going to go adrift.
It will be into a world governed by the absurd.
Yeah? Tell me all about it.
I did.
There's a voice, you see, that tells me things.
Huh?
I was informed ahead of time.
Sort of like what questions will be on the test.
Then the person behind that voice would have to be...
Indeed, who could it be?
It looks like we're not going to find anything without Nagara around.
I just happen to be on an unlucky streak.
I don't need him for this.
You've been saying that for three days now.
Hey, Tora, when did I order Ciao?
I asked you to bring me canned tuna, remember?
What's that attitude for?
Fine, no dinner for you tonight.
Don't you growl at me.
Stop screwing around!
Come on, this is no time for games, you know!
There's been even more victims!
Huh? I'm working on it here.
Well then, what do you have to show for it?
These are Mizuho's findings...
All the victims are oddballs,
and no one around them liked them.
This has led her to believe this has occurred
because they were excluded from their groups.
Somebody's probably picking on them.
You mean it's someone's power?
Could it be anything else?
Then why don't we take a look at the power list?
Hoshi asked us to survey everyone and put together a list of all our powers,
just in case something happened.
So, what do you want to know?
We want to check if there are any powers having to do with this freezing.
Okay then, I'll take this!
There's a lot we're still not sure about,
but we have a pretty good grasp of everyone's powers.
It's gotta be said that there are some powers with surprising effects,
and some that are surprisingly complex.
Huh, you're A-ranked?
What's your power?
My finger turns into a light! Isn't that amazing?!
That's all?
That gets an A rank?
Huh? It's awesome, right?
It was in that movie!
Hmm, there don't seem to be any powers that correlate with this.
But I'm not even sure if we can trust this list.
Asakaze!
Hey.
I hear you haven't cracked this yet.
And that Pony got angry at you.
Yeah, it's taking some time.
In that case, it's all good if you don't join us again.
Huh?
We're doing fine without you there.
And I just spoke to Nozomi,
who said she was fine without you around.
Oh, is that so?
Oh? You upset?
Well, if you really want, I could stick up for you,
even though you slow me down—
No, that's okay.
That's a load off. Okay, that settles it.
Sorry to interrupt.
No, it's perfectly fine.
I'm the one who should apologize.
Thanks for—
Whoa, that's so cool!
That's Kaga, right?
Hey, what was that about earlier?
What's he trying to talk you out of?
None of your concern.
Watching you back there really pissed me off.
Thanks for what?
You didn't mean a single thing you told him.
It's fine, really.
Liar.
You actually think Asakaze is a scumbag, right?
You want to slug him.
Buzz off, will you?
It's fine. It's not like I—
So lame. You don't even have the guts to fight.
There's no way I could beat him.
That doesn't matter, does it?
H-Hey...
What are you doing in here?!
I-I'm Nagara, from Class 3. Do you have a moment?
Listen, everyone is worried and out looking for you.
Are you okay?
If you don't mind, would you come back with us?
I know that's not true.
Nobody's worried about me.
True enough. No one cared one bit.
It's nice to be one of the gifted, huh?
It's so absurd, really—
always getting pushed around by them.
Kaga, how did you get here?
I don't know.
I just kept thinking that I'd had enough of this,
and before I knew it, here I was.
Before you knew it, you were here?
I'm sure God must have granted me my wish.
Huh?
H-How did you get in here?
Well, these blackout curtains are connected.
What do you mean? This isn't the only room?
Nobody's watching you, are they?
You're just playing your game all alone.
In here I can spend my time on whatever I want.
In here, even idiots can get away from being made fun of.
I don't want to work.
I like it here.
So the freeze really is some kind of rule in this world.
Serves me right for being worried.
These guys are just recluses.
Don't call them that.
So do you think you can get the four of them out of there?
And if you do, will their
creepy figures go back to normal?
Probably. But they aren't going to come out on their own.
So what do we do, then?
Do you have any practical measures you can take?
No, not yet.
We could ask Asakaze to forcibly yank them out of there, right?
That would solve this.
They said they don't want leave.
Okay, so we lure them out with money and stuff.
That won't help.
Here I was thinking you were good for something,
but I guess I was wrong!
Where'd that come from? I'm just—
This is exactly why Nozomi is giving up on you!
What does that mean?
I don't know if she likes you or whatever,
but she's been following you around like a puppy.
It grosses me out just watching!
She does not! There's no way!
There, you see?
If it doesn't bother me,
then you should just leave it alone!
That's not gonna cut it!
Not for you, and not for them!
There are some things you can't know until you meet them head-on!
Oh, so that's it.
I get it.
That's why you said you'd conduct this investigation.
You wanted to see how powerless you are.
Huh?
You were a recluse yourself,
so you lied about having powers
before we came here to show off.
Just how messed up are you,
to keep charging people for everything?
Fuck you.
I hear the investigation isn't going so well.
Why the long face?
We wouldn't have come this far without you, Nagara.
Huh?
Asakaze is nothing but talk.
He can't find anything on his own.
Is that right?
How are you doing? Close to solving your case?
We found the people who've been frozen.
But they all hate life here,
and seem to just be hiding from it.
Where were they hiding?
In a place with these blackout curtains hanging all around.
They keep going on for as far as I could see.
Amongst it all, though,
there are a number of gaps, kind of like pockets.
That's where they are.
Oh, are you saying that you found a portal to another world that wasn't in the school?
I'm not quite sure about that.
Do you remember the world you found in the audiovisual lab?
Is this another portal?
That bonehead!
Damn, does he piss me off.
Ah, this is so frustrating!
Well, maybe I went a bit too far as well.
Someone's raring to go.
This is a phenomenon created by this world's workings.
Removing those who are excluded is one of its rules.
They didn't become reclusive—
the truth is, they all...
The depths of your heart...
are always hard to dredge up.
And with that, the case is closed.
Y-Yeah.
So, what I said earlier...
I didn't really mean it.
I just got snarky—
Neither of us did, right?
Well, in any case...
The portal disappeared, huh?
Looks like it disappeared over at the school, too.
I guess it was that world that was causing the freezing.
Looks that way.
But how did those two even find another portal out here?
I had a thought about that.
Maybe Nagara does have a power...
and maybe it's the power to leap into new worlds.
And the portals are nothing more than the product of that.
Huh, is this another power relic?
A savior?
Why, who could that be?